Now, for modules and imports, Python has a pretty simple package structure, but this
has changed between Python 2 and Python 3.
So in Python 2, this dunder in it.py file was required to be in a folder for Python 2
consider that folder a package module.
In Python 3, it's no longer required, but it is still supported, and it can be useful.
Let's make a basic function, and we're going to make a new module.
So going back to VS code here, if you don't have a power shell for Windows or a bash
for Mac, I might want to create a new terminal window here.
And if you'll notice, because I have the Python extension activated, when I make a new terminal
window, VS code automatically sources the virtual environment, so I'm handy.
So I'm going to make a new folder, and I'm going to call it my math functions, and then
I'm going to see the end to there.
I'm going to make a new file, and I'm going to call it init.py.
You can also open a new window here, and save it.
In this, my math functions, and it does.py, I'm going to put this simple function, add
numbers x and y.
I want to go back up one directory, two pie workshop, because I'm going to be importing
this folder.
So let's try that again.
I'm going to type Python, and I'm going to say import my math functions.
Now I can call my math functions.add numbers, and there we go, it can use it as a library.
So generally, if you wanted, if I had a bunch of functions in here, it's valid syntax
for Python, but don't do this.
I could say, from my math functions import star, and that's going to go and import everything
from this file into my current environment.
And then I can just say add numbers 3 and 5.
But this is in great, generally, when we're using functions in these types of modules, we
want to be as specific as possible, and only import what we're going to use.
That lets us keep our environment, also called a name space in Python, as clean as possible,
and not littered with other values that we don't care about.
So if I just wanted to import add numbers, I would say from my math functions import add numbers.
And then I can say add numbers 1 and 2.
If our library has a useful name, which is should, or module, sometimes we plan on importing
quite a few things from it.
Sometimes it's okay to just say import my math functions, and then call my math functions.add
numbers, because that gives you some context of where that method came from.
So different best practices for different kind of, for different scenarios.
You can also use that as keyword, like we did with exceptions, to change how that import
is seen in your current environment or your name space.
So there's a function called preprint that we haven't talked about yet, that helps you print
out large dictionaries in a little bit of a cleaner way.
So let's say I had a dictionary with some squares in it.
Key is the number, the values of squares, and I'm going to say four nom in range, say 30.
If I just print my dictionary, it's going to be a little bit of a blob.
I can import something called pretty print, I would say from pretty print, which is the
module import, pretty print, which is the function.
Oh, sorry, it's not pretty print, it's paper print.
So I would say from paper print, import, paper print, and paper print stands for pretty print.
Now I can say, paper print, my deck, and look at that, print it out a little bit nicer,
there's some new lines here, a little bit easier for us to read.
But paper print is kind of a mouthful.
So I could also say from paper print, import, paper print as PP.
And now that that's a considerate and alias, if I didn't already import paper, it would
not be available in this context, I would just have to use PP, PP of my deck, and that
works just the same.